

## **ALESSANDRA LUCA**

MARKETING & COMMUNICATION MANAGER - SITE DIRECTOR

## PERSONAL PROFILE

Experienced Marketing
Manager with a
demonstrated history of
working in the marketing
and advertising field.
Luxury and corporate
merchandise and product
specialist., Brand
Management, Corporate
Branding, Business
Development and Marketing
Strategy.

Master's degree focused in Marketing & Communication Management from Business School Sole 24 Ore. Enthusiasm, passion and seekness for learning are my best assets, together with strong interpersonal and communication skills. Storyteller.

## CONTACTS

- Via Osteria del Guanto 5, 50122 Florence Italy
- alessandra.luca25@gmail.com
- +39 3398581267
- in http://linkedin.com/in/alessandraluca-692a1717

### SKILLS

- Strong communication and networking skills
- Resources coordinator, teamplayer
- Natural born problem solver
- The ability to work under pressure and multi-task
- The ability to forecast, report and deliver quality results
- Passionate and curious about art, trends & fashion, people, travel, yoga. food and wine, green lifestyle.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Idea Prima, Marketing & Communication Manager Site Director

### **Luxury and Corporate Merchandise**

JUL 2013 -PRESENT TIME

- Retain of key clients -Luxury area
   (Adm France for LVMH S.E. and Kering S.A.)
   Finance and Insurance, Pharma,Oil & Gas, Automotive
   (Generali Italia, ,Axa, Banca generali ,Baker Hughes).
- Define strategies of communication, supporting and developing brand awareness. Implement marketing campaigns and monitoring the process and the budget.
- Partner and advisor to client, consultant, builder and manager with team and PR agencies producing editorial plans and contents.
- Monitor ongoing marketing campaigns, incentive plans and loyalty programs; analyze market trends and tools.
- Collector, developer, sourcer of all kind of ideas and merch with a sustainable touch. Business traveller worldwide (clients, fairs and partners).

### Re-bag Ltd ,Category Manager b2b Fashion accessories and merchandise dept. Product developer and sales b2b

JAN 2011- JUN 2013

- Product development fashion accessories. (shoppers & bags, beauty case and smal gifts for Replay, Twin-set, Diesel, Patrizia Pepe, Woolrich, Liu Jo etc...)
- Monitoring follow up of mass productions
- Sourcing and benchmark accessories

#### EDUCATION

## Copy 42- Web copywrting and social media

Sept 2020 - March 2021

**Scuola Holden Torino** Corporate Storytelling and brand awareness 2020

#### Il Sole 24 ore Business School,

Milano

Master's degree Marketing and Communication Management Nov 2014.

#### Università degli Studi di Firenze

Law degree 1999 Trade mark copyright & intellectual property

## LANGUAGES &OTHERS

#### Italian

Mothertongue

#### **English**

Professional

#### **Spanish**

Intermediate

#### Russian

Beginner (in progress)

#### **Microsoft OFFICE and Outlook**

Professional use

### **Database**

Professional use Teamsystem

### CRM tools and social media

Professional use

#### Sommelier

Student (in progress)

# Blue Lab srl / Rosso Regale srl Product and Sales Home decor dept.

DEC 2006 - JAN 2011

- Marketing and sales in Home decor area (merchandise, ceramic,porcelain, stationery,xmas decorations, bags and shoppers)
- Sourcing new supplychain opportunities- eco and green in Far East (China, Vietnam etc)
- Developing products and packaging.
- Monitoring press office ongoing campaigns.

# RCS Mediagroup , Account manager b2b Italia Publishing

DEC 2005 - DEC 2006

- Managing sales and and promotional publishing campaigns. (tourism and architecture area)
- Managing mulptiple projects
- Scouting

# CHL, Marketing communication and sales Hardware and software.

DEC 2000 - DEC 2005

- Sales accounting and marketing assistant.
- · Reporting and
- Monitoring of KPI'S and performances, evaluates performance to optimize sales